University at Albany Magazine; Collection ua950.009
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
University at Albany Magazine Collection
1967-2014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany
ua950.009
2.66 cubic ft.
This collection is made up of copies of the Carillon and University at Albany Magazine.
Collection X
Administrative History
The Carillon began publication in 1967, naming itself after the tower on the still newly built campus. It was a school newspaper detailing events on campus such as newly appointed faculty, sporting events, and alumni news. It was published by the Alumni Association. In the Spring of 1987 the University at Albany Magazine began publishing. The content was similar, focusing on campus events, giving alumni spotlights. It was published seasonally in the Fall, Winter, and Spring. The magazine was originally published by the University Relations Office.
In the Spring of 1992 the two publication combined being renamed the University at Albany Magazine, with The Carillon. The publication was larger, once again containing similar content as previously, and also contained information on research at the university, discussing the work of faculty. This continued this way until the Fall of 2000 when the title returned to being the University at Albany Magazine. The carillon was still in the publication, typically taking up the second half and consisting of alumni news and notes. The target of both these publications is Alumni, parents, and faculty of the University.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the publication the Carillon and the University at Albany Magazine. The Carillon was published independently from 1967 to 1991. The collection also has the independent publication of the University at Albany Magazine dating from 1987 to 1991. In 1992 the publications merged together and have maintained this status up to today.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is ordered chronologically.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Alumni and Alumnae; College Publications; UAlbany Reference Collections
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 1, Number 1, 1987 Spring (Box 1, Folder 1)
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 2, Number 1, 1987 Fall (Box 1, Folder 2)
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 2, Number 2, 1988 Spring (Box 1, Folder 3)
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 3, Number 1, 1989 Winter (Box 1, Folder 4)
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 3, Number 2, 1989 Fall (Box 1, Folder 5)
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 4, Number 1, 1990 Summer (Box 1, Folder 6)
- University at Albany Magazine, Volume 4, Number 2, 1991 Winter (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1991 Fall (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1992 Spring (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1992 Fall (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1993 Spring (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1993 Fall (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1994 Spring (Box 1, Folder 13)
  General
  2 copies
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1994 Fall (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1995 Spring (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1995 Fall (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1996 Spring (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1996 Fall (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1997 Spring (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1997 Fall (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1998 Spring (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1998 Fall (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1999 Spring (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Albany, University at Albany Magazine with The Carillion, 1999 Fall (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Albany Magazine, 2000 January (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Albany Magazine, 2000 Spring (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Albany Magazine, 2000 Fall (Box 1, Folder 27)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2001 January (Box 1, Folder 28)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2001 Spring (Box 1, Folder 29)
  3 copies
- UAlbany Magazine, 2001 Fall (Box 1, Folder 30)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2002 January (Box 1, Folder 31)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2002 Spring (Box 1, Folder 32)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2002 Fall (Box 1, Folder 33)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2003 January (Box 2, Folder 1)
- UAlbany Magazine, Special Campaign Issue, 2003 Spring (Box 2, Folder 2)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2003 Fall (Box 2, Folder 3)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2004 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2004 Spring (Box 2, Folder 5)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2004 Fall (Box 2, Folder 6)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2005 January (Box 2, Folder 7)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2005 Spring (Box 2, Folder 8)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2005 Fall (Box 2, Folder 9)
- UAlbany Magazine, Special Metropolitan New York Issue, 2005 December (Box 2, Folder 10)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2006 Spring (Box 2, Folder 11)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2006 Fall (Box 2, Folder 12)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2007 Spring (Box 2, Folder 13)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2007 Fall (Box 2, Folder 14)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2008 Winter (Box 2, Folder 15)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2008 Fall (Box 2, Folder 16)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2009 Spring (Box 2, Folder 17)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2009 Fall (Box 2, Folder 18)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2010 Spring (Box 2, Folder 19)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2010 Fall (Box 2, Folder 20)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2011 Spring (Box 2, Folder 21)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2011 Fall
- UAlbany Magazine, 2012 Spring (Box 3, Folder 1)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2012 Fall (Box 3, Folder 2)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2013 Spring (Box 3, Folder 3)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2013 Fall (Box 3, Folder 4)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2014 Spring (Box 3, Folder 5)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2014 Fall (Box 3, Folder 6)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2015 Spring (Box 3, Folder 7)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2015 Fall (Box 3, Folder 8)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2016 Spring
- UAlbany Magazine, 2016 Fall
- UAlbany Magazine, 2017 Spring
- UAlbany Magazine, 2017 Fall
- UAlbany Magazine, 2018 Spring (Box 3, Folder 9)
- UAlbany Magazine, 2018 Fall
- UAlbany Magazine, 175th Anniversary Edition, 2019 Spring (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 175th Anniversary Edition Timeline Insert, 2019 Spring (Box 3, Folder 11)